( thunder crashing )
( bell tolling )
Kirito: HEY, EUGEO,
ISN’T THAT THE 4:30 BELL?
( Eugeo gasps )
YEAH, IT IS.
Kirito: THEY’RE BOTH LATE.
THAT’S NOT GOOD.
RONIE AND TIESE HAVE
NEVER BEEN LATE BEFORE.
( Eugeo grunts )
( Kirito sighs )
I GOT A BAD FEELING ABOUT THIS.
I’M GONNA GO OVER TO THEIR DORM
AND SEE IF THEY’RE STILL THERE.
THEY MIGHT BE ON THEIR WAY OVER,
SO HOLD DOWN THE FORT
’TIL I GET BACK.
Eugeo: WAIT.
WHY ARE YOU GOING OUT THAT WAY?
USE THE D--
I WISH HE’D STOP
USING THE WINDOW.
♪
( knock on door )
( Eugeo sighs )
THANK GOODNESS. WE WERE...
Girl: UH, WOULD YOU HAPPEN
TO BE ELITE DISCIPLE EUGEO?
Eugeo: Y-YES. AND YOU ARE?
Girl: MY NAME IS FRENICA CESKY,
ONE OF THE PRIMARY TRAINEES.
I DO APOLOGIZE
FOR COMING TO SEE YOU
WITHOUT AN APPOINTMENT, SIR.
I NEED YOUR HELP.
I DON’T KNOW WHO ELSE TO ASK!
Eugeo: IT’S ALL RIGHT.
TELL ME WHAT’S WRONG.
Frenica: I KNOW
YOU’VE GONE ABOVE AND BEYOND
IN REGARDS TO MY ISSUE
WITH LORD ZIZEK.
I REALLY CAN’T EVEN BEGIN
TO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY, TONIGHT
I RECEIVED WORD FROM HIM
THAT I AM TO--THAT IS...
HE ORDERED ME
TO PERFORM A SERVICE
THAT I’M MUCH TOO EMBARRASSED
TO REPEAT.
( Eugeo gasps )
( thunder crashing )
Frenica: I TOLD RONIE AND TIESE
THAT IF HE KEPT
GIVING ME ORDERS LIKE THIS,
THERE’S NO WAY
I’D BE ABLE TO STAY HERE.
I’D HAVE TO LEAVE THE ACADEMY.
WHEN I TOLD THEM ALL THIS,
THEY SAID THEY’D GO
TRY TO REASON WITH HIM,
BUT THEY STILL
HAVEN’T COME BACK.
I’M AFRAID
OF WHAT THAT COULD MEAN.
Eugeo: SO AM I.
STAY HERE ’TIL I GET BACK.
♪
SO THIS IS HOW
THEY WANT TO GET EVEN,
BY HURTING RONIE AND TIESE!
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
( pounding on door )
( Eugeo grunts )
( pounding )
Humbert: PLEASE, ENTER!
♪
WE JUST UNCORKED
THIS 50-YEAR-OLD BOTTLE
FROM THE WESTERN EMPIRE.
DO JOIN US.
COMMONERS NEVER TASTE
SUCH DELIGHTS.
( Eugeo sighs )
I’M AFRAID I MUST DECLINE.
ANOTHER MATTER BRINGS ME HERE.
I’D LIKE TO KNOW IF MY PAGE,
PRIMARY TRAINEE TIESE SCHTRINEN,
AND DISCIPLE KIRITO’S PAGE,
PRIMARY TRAINEE RONIE ARABEL,
CAME HERE THIS EVENING.
Raios: I SEE.
WHAT A COINCIDENCE
THAT THOSE TWO GIRLS
BELONG TO SIR KIRITO
AND YOURSELF.
THEIR AUDACIOUSNESS
WAS RATHER SURPRISING,
APPROACHING SUCH HIGHLY REGARDED
STUDENTS AS HUMBERT AND MYSELF
AND WITHOUT SO MUCH
AS A FORMAL INVITATION.
THEIR LACK OF COUTH IS FAMILIAR.
THAT SAID,
THEY DO NEED TO BE CAREFUL.
ASSERTIVENESS CAN SOMETIMES
BE CONSTRUED AS DISRESPECT.
DO YOU NOT AGREE,
DISCIPLE EUGEO?
( Eugeo gasps )
WE CAN TALK ABOUT
YOUR OPINIONS ANOTHER TIME.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHERE TIESE AND RONIE ARE!
( grunts )
( gasps )
( Humbert chuckles )
( Raios chuckles )
( Eugeo gasps )
WHAT IS THIS?!
( girls gasping )
WH-WHAT IS THE MEANING
OF THIS, LORD RAIOS?!
Raios: THESE MEASURES
WERE UNAVOIDABLE, SIR EUGEO.
PRIMARY TRAINEES SCHTRINEN
AND ARABEL DISRESPECTED US
TO SUCH A DEGREE,
MY HAND WAS FORCED.
Eugeo: DISRESPECTED?
Humbert: THEY CLEARLY FORGOT
WHO THEY WERE ADDRESSING.
THESE TWO LESSER NOBLES
HAD THE GALL
TO ACCUSE ME,
A SUPERIOR RANKING NOBLE,
OF USING MY PAGE AS A MEANS
TO SATISFY MY LUSTFUL URGES.
AFTER EVERYTHING I’VE DONE
TO TRY TO GUIDE FRENICA
DOWN THE PROPER PATH.
TALK ABOUT UNGRATEFUL.
( Eugeo gasps )
Raios: BUT LO AND BEHOLD,
THE PLOT DOTH THICKEN.
THEY MADE THE PREPOSTEROUS CLAIM
THAT AS HUMBERT’S ROOMMATE,
I WAS JUST AS RESPONSIBLE
FOR HIS ACTIONS AS HE WAS.
THE IDEA OF SOMEONE
LIKE HER ASKING ME,
THE ELDEST
OF A THIRD-RANK HOUSEHOLD,
"HAVE YOU NO HONOR AS A NOBLE?"
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD
SUCH LUNACY?
( both chuckle )
Eugeo: SIR, EVEN IF EVERYTHING
HAPPENED AS YOU DESCRIBED,
TYING THEM UP AND LOCKING THEM
IN YOUR BEDROOM,
THAT GOES WAY BEYOND YOUR
AUTHORITY TO PUNISH TRAINEES!
Raios: YOU’RE REFERRING
TO THE SCHOOL GUIDELINES?
MY DEAR EUGEO, YOU NEED
TO THINK MUCH LARGER THAN THAT.
DO YOU REMEMBER THIS PASSAGE
FROM THE ACADEMY’S RULES:
"HIGHER LAW TAKES PRECEDENCE
IN ALL CASES"?
( Eugeo gasps )
( Raios chuckles )
HIGHER LAW REFERS
TO THE TABOO INDEX,
AS WELL AS BASIC IMPERIAL LAW.
IN OTHER WORDS,
WHAT I CAN EXERCISE
ON THESE GIRLS OF LOWER RANK
ISN’T A RESULT OF AUTHORITY
GIVEN TO ME BY THIS ACADEMY,
BUT MY POWER AS A NOBLE!
SUCH IS MY SOVEREIGN RIGHT!
( girls scream )
STOP YOUR SQUIRMING,
AND TAKE YOUR PUNISHMENT
LIKE A GOOD GIRL.
Eugeo: LEAVE THEM ALONE!
Raios:
HOLD YOUR GROUND, COMMONER!
THIS JUDGMENT
IS BEING CARRIED OUT
IN COMPLETE ACCORDANCE
WITH BASIC IMPERIAL LAW
AND THE TABOO INDEX.
TO OBSTRUCT SUCH A DECREE
WOULD BE DEEMED A CRIMINAL ACT.
IF YOU TAKE
EVEN ONE STEP CLOSER,
YOU WILL BECOME A CRIMINAL
IN THE EYES OF THE LAW!
Eugeo: YOU CAN’T DO THIS.
( grunts )
MY LEGS!
( grunting )
Ronie: NO! PLEASE, DON'T!
Tiese: NO, NO! PLEASE, NO!
EUGEO! EUGEO!
Kirito: THERE ARE THINGS
YOU JUST SHOULDN’T DO,
EVEN IF THERE’S
NO LAW AGAINST IT.
AT THE SAME TIME, THERE MIGHT
BE STUFF YOU SHOULD DO,
EVEN IF THE LAWS
SAY YOU SHOULDN’T.
( Eugeo grunting )
( thunder crashing )
Ronie: NO! STOP IT!
Tiese: EUGEO! HELP ME! PLEASE!
I'M BEGGING YOU! DON'T LET HIM DO THIS!
Eugeo: RONIE AND TIESE
HAD THE COURAGE
TO STAND UP FOR THEIR FRIEND.
WHAT KIND OF LAW
JUSTIFIES PUNISHMENT FOR THAT?!
RAIOS AND HUMBERT
ARE GOING TO DEFILE THEM!
WHAT KIND OF LAW
DOES NOTHING TO STOP THEM?!
EUGEO!
IF UPHOLDING LAWS LIKE THESE
IS MY DUTY, THEN...
THEN I...
I...
( grunting )
( screams )
WHAT’S GOING ON?!
WAIT. THIS HAPPENED BEFORE.
( grunting )
THIS IS EVIL!
I HAVE TO...
STOP THEM!
Tiese: HELP US!
PLEASE! EUGEO!
( Raios chuckles )
( both laugh )
( Eugeo screaming )
♪
( Humbert gasps )
( screams )
( Eugeo gasping )
Humbert: MY ARM.
MY ARM IS BLEEDING. HELP!
IT’S NOT STOPPING.
MY LIFE IS DECREASING!
PLEASE, LORD RAIOS,
USE THE SACRED ARTS!
NO, WAIT. A NORMAL SPELL
WON’T HEAL THIS IN TIME.
LIFE ENERGY! HURRY!
SHARE SOME OF YOURS WITH ME!
( whimpering )
( Raios scoffs )
WHAT A THRILL. ( laughs )
NEVER BEFORE HAVE I WITNESSED
SOMEONE COMMIT
SUCH A HEINOUS CRIME!
THE SCOPE OF A NOBLE’S AUTHORITY
ONLY APPLIES TO LESSER NOBLES
AND RUN-OF-THE-MILL
PLEBEIAN SCUM.
( grunts )
BUT FOR ROGUES WHO’VE
BROKEN THE TABOO INDEX,
EXCEPTIONS CAN BE MADE!
( thunder crashes )
( chuckles )
I’VE NEVER USED MY SWORD
TO CUT OFF
SOMEONE’S HEAD BEFORE.
I WILL GAIN
EVEN MORE POWER FROM IT!
( thunder crashes )
YOU ARE NO DISCIPLE NOW.
NO, YOU ARE A CRIMINAL.
IN ACCORDANCE
WITH THE POWERS GRANTED TO ME
AS A THIRD-RANK NOBLE,
I, RAIOS ANTINOUS,
SHALL EXECUTE YOU!
( grunts )
( Eugeo gasps )
KIRITO.
Kirito: BACK OFF, RAIOS.
NO WAY AM I
GONNA LET YOU HURT HIM.
Raios: GOOD OF YOU TO JOIN
THE PARTY, DISCIPLE KIRITO.
HOWEVER, I’M AFRAID
YOU’RE A HAIR TOO LATE.
THIS FILTHY SWINE
VIOLATED THE TABOO INDEX
AND IS A CRIMINAL,
SO YOU BEST STAND DOWN.
I SHALL CUT HIS HEAD
FROM HIS NECK,
JUST LIKE THE HEADS
OF YOUR PRECIOUS FLOWERS!
Kirito: I DON’T GIVE A DAMN
ABOUT YOUR TABOOS OR NOBLE CRAP.
EUGEO’S A FRIEND OF MINE,
BUT YOU,
YOU’RE LESS THAN NOTHING.
YOU’RE EVEN LOWER
THAN THE GODDAMN GOBLINS!
( Raios gasping )
( laughs )
TO THINK THAT NOT ONE,
BUT TWO PEASANTS
WOULD COMMIT
SUCH HEINOUS CRIMES!
THIS MEANS I CAN DO AWAY WITH
BOTH OF YOU AT THE SAME TIME!
WHAT A JOYOUS DAY THIS IS.
SURELY THIS IS A DIVINE BLESSING
FROM THE GODDESS STACIA!
( Eugeo gasping )
Kirito: I GOT THIS.
♪
( Eugeo gasps )
( Raios laughs )
THAT PIECE OF JUNK WILL SHATTER
AGAINST MY SECRET TECHNIQUE!
Kirito: WE’LL SEE ABOUT THAT!
( thunder crashing )
( Raios yells )
( Kirito yells )
Raios: WELL, NOW. HOW IS THAT?
YOU CAN’T POSSIBLY HAVE THOUGHT
I, RAIOS ANTINOUS,
WOULD STRUGGLE
AGAINST A PISSANT LIKE YOU!
( yells )
Eugeo: KIRITO!
( Raios grunting )
( Kirito grunting )
( yelling )
♪
( Raios screaming )
MY ARMS!
WH-WH-WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?!
THE BLOOD, IT WON’T STOP!
( gasping )
- HUMBERT!
- ( Humbert gasps )
Raios: HURRY!
MAKE THE BLEEDING STOP!
UNTIE YOUR ROPES,
AND BIND MY ARMS NOW!
Humbert: I CAN’T DO THAT!
IF I UNTIE THIS,
MY LIFE WILL BE DECREASED!
YOU CAN’T ASK ME
TO VIOLATE THE TABOO INDEX!
Raios: HANG THE LAW! HELP ME!
IT’S NOT STOPPING! HUMBERT!
TABOO--YOU MUST--
M-MY LIFE--MY LIFE IS--
( gasping )
TABOO!
( gasps ) MY LIFE--
THE BLOOD! TABOO!
MY LIFE.
MY BLOOD.
THE TABOO.
MY LIFE.
TABOO. LIFE.
THE TABOO! ( gasping )
L-LIFE.
Kirito:
I’LL TIE ’EM OFF FOR YOU.
Raios: MY LIFE!
TABOO!
BLOOD--TABOO!
- ( Kirito gasps )
- Raios: BLOOD! TABOO! TABOO!
TABOO! LIFE! TABOO! LIFE!
TABOO--( overlapping words )
( electronic wail )
( abrupt stop )
- ( wind blowing )
- ( blood trickling )
Kirito: WHAT THE HELL?
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIS FLUCTLIGHT?
( Humbert whimpering )
( wails )
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE TO HIM?!
HE’S--
( whimpering )
AHH! MURDERER!
MONSTER!
( whimpering )
Tiese: I’M SO SORRY.
PLEASE FORGIVE ME, EUGEO.
THIS IS--THIS IS ALL MY FAULT!
Eugeo: NO, IT’S NOT.
YOU’RE NOT TO BLAME FOR THIS.
I AM. THIS HAPPENED BECAUSE I
DIDN’T THINK IT THROUGH.
IT ISN’T YOUR FAULT, TIESE.
Tiese: BUT, EUGEO...
YOUR EYE.
Eugeo: ALL THAT MATTERS NOW
IS THAT YOU AND RONIE ARE SAFE.
I WISH I GOT HERE SOONER.
I’M SORRY.
IT’S MY FAULT THIS ALL HAPPENED.
( Tiese sobbing )
( Ronie sobbing )
( Kirito grunts )
♪
( both gasp )
( Kirito gasps )
( humming )
Eugeo: I’VE SEEN THIS BEFORE,
SOMEWHERE A LONG TIME AGO.
Kirito: HOLD ON TO HER!
DON’T LET HER SEE IT!
Stranger: A SINGULAR UNIT
HAS BEEN DETECTED.
TRACING ITS I.D.
COORDINATES FIXED.
REPORT COMPLETE.
( Eugeo sighs )
( curtains rustling )
Humbert: AHH! MURDERER!
MONSTER!
Eugeo: HE’S RIGHT. WHAT AM I?
I’M NO BETTER
THAN THOSE GOBLINS!
Kirito: NO, EUGEO,
YOU’RE HUMAN, SAME AS ME.
SURE, SOMETIMES WE SCREW UP,
BUT WE CAN LEARN FROM IT
AND MAKE IT RIGHT.
THAT’S BEING HUMAN.
Eugeo: KIRITO.
( birds chirping )
( footsteps )
( Kirito sighs )
( keys jangling )
( lock clicking )
Azurica: COME OUT.
STEP CLOSER.
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE LUMINOUS ELEMENT.
RECONSTRUCT LOST ORGAN.
GO ON. OPEN IT.
Eugeo: YES, MA’AM.
♪
( gasps )
THANK YOU FOR FIXING IT,
MS. AZURICA!
Azurica: YOU ARE MOST WELCOME.
NOW LISTEN CAREFULLY.
YOUR ESCORT IS COMING FOR YOU.
I MUST HAND YOU OVER TO THEM
AND HAVE NO CHOICE
IN THE MATTER.
I’D LIKE TO SAY A FEW WORDS
BEFORE THAT HAPPENS.
DISCIPLE EUGEO,
BREAKING THAT SEAL IS SOMETHING
I WAS NEVER ABLE TO DO,
AND, AS A RESULT, YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO GO WHERE I CANNOT.
HAVE FAITH IN YOUR SWORD
AND IN YOUR FRIEND.
DISCIPLE KIRITO,
IN ALL THE TIME YOU WERE HERE,
I NEVER GOT TO KNOW
WHO YOU REALLY ARE.
THAT SAID, I DO KNOW
EVERYTHING HERE WILL CHANGE
ONCE YOU REACH THE TOWER.
EVEN IF
I CAN’T HELP YOU DIRECTLY,
I’LL BE PRAYING THAT YOU
FIND THE TRUTH, ALWAYS.
♪
Eugeo: I’VE SEEN
THIS KIND OF BLUE AND GOLD
SOMEWHERE BEFORE, BUT WHERE?
Woman: I AM THE INTEGRITY KNIGHT
WHO OVERSEES
THE CAPITAL OF CENTORIA.
( Eugeo gasps )
Alice: I AM
ALICE SYNTHESIS THIRTY.
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪